

Software Developer.

CONTACT INFO

maxwittek+resume@gmail.com Seattle, WA

ONLINE

github.com/wittekm LinkedIn

SKILLS

Relational and graph DBs

Java

Python

Typescript w/ React

C++

Ruby w/ Rails

As this list grows, it's easiest to say that I pick up new technologies and practices pretty easily.

Profile

Full-stack software engineer with 7+ years experience in building <u>distributed services</u>, <u>native libraries</u>, and <u>frontend experiences</u>. I'm happiest when improving a well-tested, statically typed codebase, at an exciting and ethical company (meaning - an immediate 'no thank you' to adtech or investment firms - sorry!).

Experience

Dropbox (2015-Current)

Software Engineer 3

<u>Tech lead</u> on our Slack integration, Gmail addon and Azure Active Directory integration. Primarily owned task management and architecture for these projects, but I still code ~50% of my time. Frequently worked together with external business partners and engineers at Slack, Microsoft and Google, respectively.

Software Engineer 2 & 3

Developer responsible for worldwide payments processing, product catalog, ETLs, revenue reporting, and compliance.

Amazon.com (2012-2015)

Software Development Engineer II

On loan to an NDA'd project, working on portions of the Kindle cross-platform layout & rendering engine in C++03.

Tech: worked with Boost libraries, OpenGL ES, Android NDK and Cocoa.

Software Development Engineer I & II

Member of the Kindle Content Inspection & Automation team, developing technology to ensure that only quality books are made available on the Kindle Store, and that publishers have the rights to the content.

Tech: Java services, SpringMVC sites, Ruby on Rails sites, distributed computing via Amazon SWF/SNS/SQS, SQL & NoSQL (DynamoDB).

Common patterns: Event Sourcing, Event Bus / ESB.

Internships

Amazon.com (2011), Crestron Electronics (2009), BlackRock Solutions (2008)

Education

University of Michigan (2008-2012)

Bachelors of Science in Engineering, Computer Science

Relevant classes included UI Development, Intro to Artificial Intelligence, Advanced Programming and Design Patterns, Operating Systems, Computer Organization/Architecture, Data Structures & Algorithms, Natural Language Processing.